Jacobs family papers, 1861-1909 (bulk 1878-1890)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series I: Unbound Papers, 1861-1896
  - Unbound Records: Agency Pima County Bank of Tombstone, Cochise County Bank, First National Bank of Tucson, and Santa Cruz Valley Bank, 1877-1891
    - Arizona National Bank: Transactions, general. 1896 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Arizona National Bank: Transactions with Farmers and Merchants' Bank. 1896 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Arizona National Bank: Transactions with Phoenix National Bank. 1896 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Arizona National Bank: Transactions with London, Paris and American Bank. 1896 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Arizona National Bank: Transactions with State National Bank, El Paso. 1896 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Series II: Bound Volumes, 1867-1909
  Series II consists of five subseries: Bound volumes of L.M. Jacobs and Co., 1867-1880; Bound volumes of Pima County Bank, First National Bank of Tucson, Bank of Tucson, and Consolidated Bank of Tucson, 1879-1809; Bound volumes of Agency Pima County Bank, and Cochise County Bank, 1880-1889; Bound volumes of Arizona National Bank, 1889-1909; and Miscellaneous bound volume, circa. 1896. The volumes consist of journals and ledgers which include invoice records, daily sales blotters, daily office blotters, daily cash sales, and other records.
  - Bound volumes of L.M. Jacobs and Co., 1867-1880
    - Journal, daily accounts of sales and returns. July10, 1869-February 28, 1870 (Volume 1)
    - Journal. May 1, 1872-April 30, 1873 (Volume 1A)
    - Journal. May 1, 1873-May 31, 1875 (Volume 2)
    - Journal. June 1, 1875-September 30, 1878 (Volume 3)
    - Ledger, summary accounts by customer, itemized merchandise. March, 1868-March, 1870 (Volume 4)
    - Ledger, merchandise not itemzied. March, 1870-April, 1873 (Volume 5)
    - Ledger, itemized merchandise. January-May, 1873 (Volume 6)
    - Ledger, merchandise not itemized. July, 1875-March, 1878 (Volume 7)
    - Invoice record, itemized lists of goods by supplier, gives method of transportation including ships, U.S. mail, stage, etc. January, 1869-August, 1872 (Volume 8)
    - Invoice record. September, 1872-October, 1876 (Volume 9)
    - Invoice record. October, 1876-August, 1879 (Volume 10)
    - Daily sales blotter; earliest daily record of sales, gives customer name, items purchased and price. July 7, 1867-December 30, 1868 (Volume 11)
    - Daily sales blotter. October 17, 1870-October 15, 1871 (Volume 12)
    - Daily sales blotter. October 16, 1871-April 30, 1872 (Volume 13)
    - Daily sales blotter. May 1, 1872-March 1, 1873 (Volume 14)
    - Daily sales blotter. December 3, 1873-September 30, 1874 (Volume 15)
    - Daily sales blotter. May 1-September 30, 1875 (Volume 16)
    - Daily sales blotter. October 1, 1875-January 31, 1876 (Volume 17)
    - Daily sales blotter. February 1-October 14, 1876 (Volume 18)
    - Daily sales blotter. October 16, 1876-April 7, 1877 (Volume 19)
    - Daily sales blotter. April 9, 1877-March 30, 1878 (Volume 20)
    - Daily sales blotter. April 1-October 31, 1878 (Volume 21)
    - Daily sales blotter. November 1, 1878-June 30, 1879 (Volume 22)
    - Daily sales blotter. July1, 1879-May 27, 1880 (Volume 23)
    - Office blotter, daily financial entries consist of debits to cash or bills receivable and credits to merchandise. November 1, 1875-November 30, 1876 (Volume 24)
    - Office blotter. December 4, 1876-April 30, 1878 (Volume 25)
    - Office blotter. May 1-October 5, 1878 (Volume 26)
    - Office blotter. October 8, 1878-April 17, 1879 (Volume 27)
    - Office blotter. April 18, 1879-December, 1880 (Volume 28)
    - Office blotter, summary records. 1870-1884 (Volume 29)
    - Branch store accounts. 1873-1875 (Volume 30)
    - Daily cash sales, Branch 2 stock book, statement of account of L. Carrillo. May 1, 1875-July 31, 1876 (Volume 31)
    - Daily cash sales. August1, 1876-August 4, 1877 (Volume 32)
    - Daily cash sales, agreement among Tucson merchants on the price of flour and other goods, accounts of merchandise shipments received in Tucson. August 6,1877-January 16, 1878 (Volume 33)
    - Daily cash sales. January 17, 1878-June 21, 1879 (Volume 34)
    - Daily cash sales, inventories. June 23, 1879-June 11, 1880 (Volume 35)
    - Santa Rita store accounts and ledger (in Spanish). February, 1872-February, 1879 (Volume 36)
    - Miscellaneous store records (includes Santa Rita store accounts). 1868-1880 (Volume 37)
    - Receipt books (stubs); lists customer, date, place delivered, and items delivered. Places shipped to include Camp Grant, Florence, Santa Rita Mines; customers include J.B. Allen and others. August 17, 1875-January 18, 1879 (Volume 38)
    - Letter book (carbons); includes letters from Barron Jacobs to M.I. Jacobs, Lionel Jacobs, and freighters. Some give detailed information about shipping, freighting, travel conditions, business conditions, and contracting as supplier to government camps. The letters from Barron to M.I. and Lionel respond to letters which are filed in Box 1 of this collection. August 4, 1871-August 13, 1872 (Volume 39)
    - Letter book (carbons); includes letters to Lionel and M.I. Jacobs, David Neahr, Camp Thomas and others. June 22, 1877-November 30, 1878 (Volume 40)
    - Distilled Spirits Received and Sold; printed forms give who and where sent, how many gallons, and who inspected by. Customers include Camp Grant, Abraham Franklin in Safford, and others. 1876-1880 (Volume 41)
    - Florence Steam Mill Accounts (flour); also contains an inventory (chiefly in Spanish). August, 1880-May, 1881 (Volume 42)
    - Inventory records. 1871-1883 (Volume 43)
  - Bound volumes of Pima County Bank, First National Bank of Tucson, Bank of Tucson, and Consolidated Bank of Tucson, 1879-1809
    - Journal A, daily financial transactions. 1879 (Volume 44)
    - Journal B. January, 1880-April 20, 1881 (Volume 45)
    - Journal C, monthly records. April 21, 1881-April 17, 1882 (Volume 46)
    - Ledger A, financial transactions by account. 1879 (Volume 47)
    - Ledger B. 1880-1882 (Volume 48)
    - Ledger C. 1881-1882 (Volume 49)
    - General journal. August 18, 1884-January, 1887 (Volume 50)
    - General ledger. 1882-1885 (Volume 51)
    - Cash journal. October 21, 1879-February 24, 1882 (Volume 52)
    - Mexican silver journal. April, 1882-January 24, 1885 (Volume 53)
    - Cash book. November 1, 1882-May 16, 1883 (Volume 54)
    - Cash book. May 17-November 26, 1883 (Volume 55)
    - Cash book. November 27, 1883-June 11, 1884 (Volume 56)
    - Cash book. June 12-December 23, 1884 (Volume 57)
    - Cash book. February 21-August 13, 1885 (Volume 58)
    - Cash book. August 15, 1885-February, 1886 (Volume 59)
    - Cash book. February 4-June 4, 1886 (Volume 60)
    - Trial balance sheets, currency and Mexican silver, depositors daily balances: includes S.M. Franklin, Samuel Hughes, H.S. Stevens, W.L. Vail, J.H. Behan, J.C. Hardy, Sabino Otero, C. Cameron, W. Barnes, M. Samaniego, J.O. Dunbar, Wm. Oury, others. 1881-1887 (Volume 61)
    - General balances. July, 1882-August, 1884 (Volume 62)
    - General balances. August, 1884-February, 1885 (Volume 63)
    - Discount register, gives promissor, endorser, where payable, discounted for, date, amount of note, when due, and when paid. Customers include Juan Elias, Peter Kitchen, Oscar Buckalew, Bernabe Robles, Leopoldo Carrillo, L.C. Hughes, H.C. Hooker, and others. 1882-1887 (Volume 64)
    - Index diary, calendar of matters requiring attention of a special date. 1882 (Volume 65)
    - Certificates of deposit (stubs). March 13, 1883-August 15, 1884 (Volume 66)
    - Drafts, money order stubs on Pacific Bank, San Francisco. April 17, 1882-April 2, 1883 (Volume 67)
    - Drafts, money order stubs on Chemical National Bank, New York. April 17, 1882-March 3, 1883 (Volume 68)
    - Records of payments for Governmental and Other Agencies, stubs, includes Internal Revenue, surveys of public lands, military, etc. July 19, 1882-April 28, 1883 (Volume 69)
    - Records of Payments for Government and Other Agencies, stubs. May 1-November 30, 1883 (Volume 70)
    - Record of Payments for Government and Other Agencies, stubs. December 1, 1883-July 24, 1884 (Volume 71)
    - Draft Register for Correspondent Banks, doing business with the Agency Bank: Chemical National Bank; Farmers and Merchants' Bank; and Pacific National Bank. April-July, 1882 (Volume 72)
    - Draft Register for Correspondent Banks, doing business with the First National Bank of Tucson: Bank of California, San Francisco; Chemical National Bank, N.Y.; Farmers and Merchants' Bank, L.A.; National Park Bank, N.Y.; and Pacific Bank, San Francisco. 1882-1883 (Volume 73)
    - Draft Register for Correspondent Banks, doing business with the First National Bank of Tucson and the Bank of Tucson: Bank of California, San Francisco; Chemical National Bank, N.Y.; Farmers and Merchants' Bank, L.A.; First National Bank, Chicago; Fourth National Bank, St. Louis; Massachusetts National Bank; National Park Bank, N.Y.; and Second National Bank of New Mexico, Santa Fe. 1883-1887 (Volume 74)
    - Collection registers. March, 1880-October, 1886 (Volume 75)
    - Remittance register; also contains Register of Certificates of deposit. Certificates of deposit give date, number, name, currency or Mexican silver, and date paid. Names include Peter Kitchen, Wong Cong You, C.A. Shibbell, Charlie, Abraham Franklin, Bernabe Robles, Wah Sing, and others. Remittance register includes name of drawer, where drawn, endorser, drawee, where payable, and amount; involves transactions between local companies and companies in other states. July, 1880-September, 1882 (Volume 76)
    - Miscellaneous items, includes stub record of original shareholders of First National Bank of Tucson, letters of credit for travelers in Europe, and accounts of U.S. Army Paymaster. 1879-1889 (Volume 77)
    - Letter book (carbons); consist of brief one half page bank business letters signed by William A. Scott, Jr., Manager, L.M. Jacobs, or B.M. Jacobs. February 8, 1879-January 15, 1880 (Volume 78)
    - Letter book (carbons). January 16-July 17, 1880 (Volume 79)
    - Letter book (carbons). July 19-December 21, 1880 (Volume 80)
    - Letter book (carbons). December 22, 1880-May 18, 1881 (Volume 81)
    - Letter book (carbons). May 18-November 14, 1881 (Volume 82)
    - Letter book (carbons). November 14, 1881-February 23, 1882 (Volume 83)
    - Letter book (carbons). February 23-July 22, 1882 (Volume 84)
    - Letter book (carbons). April 17-July 24, 1882 (Volume 85)
    - Letter book (carbons). July 25-November 8, 1882 (Volume 86)
    - Letter book (carbons). November 9, 1882-February 28, 1883 (Volume 87)
    - Letter book (carbons). March 1-June 25, 1883 (Volume 88)
    - Letter book (carbons). June 16-October 30, 1883 (Volume 89)
    - Letter book (carbons). July-October 8, 1884 (Volume 90)
    - Letter book (carbons). October 8, 1884-January 22, 1885 (Volume 91)
    - Letter book (carbons). January 23-June 12, 1886 (Volume 92)
    - Letter book (carbons). June 12-November 26, 1886 (Volume 93)
    - Telegrams (carbons). April 18, 1882-February 28, 1883 (Volume 94)
    - Telegrams (carbons). March 15, 1884-February 7, 1885 (Volume 95)
    - Postals (carbons). July 5, 1882-February, 1885 (Volume 96)
    - Postals (carbons). February, 1885-April, 1887 (Volume 97)
  - Bound volumes of Agency Pima County Bank, and Cochise County Bank, 1880-1889
    - Journal, daily transactions giving names and amounts. November 15-December 31, 1880 (Volume 98)
    - Journal C. September 19, 1881-April 29, 1882 (Volume 99)
    - Journal Number 1. May 1, 1882-August 14, 1883 (Volume 100)
    - Journal Number 2. August 15, 1883-November 29, 1884 (Volume 101)
    - Cash Journal Number 4. March 20, 1886-September 24, 1887 (Volume 102)
    - Cash Journal Number 5. September 27, 1887-July 24, 1889 (Volume 103)
    - Ledger C. January-April, 1882 (Volume 104)
    - Ledger. May, 1882-December, 1886 (Volume 105)
    - Index to Ledger (volume 105). May, 1882-December, 1886 (Volume 106)
    - Ledger. 1887-1888 (Volume 107)
    - Index to unidentified ledger. No Date (Volume 108)
    - Minutes of meetings of stockholders and Board of Directors of Cochise County Bank. March 18-April 21, 1882 (Volume 109)
    - Transfer of Agency Pima County Bank to Cochise County Bank; consists of summary of accounts transferred including names and amounts. Names include J.O. Dunbar, John P. Clum, J.H. Behan, and others. April 29, 1882 (Volume 110)
    - Daily cash blotter. December 6, 1881-April 15, 1882 (Volume 111)
    - Daily cash blotter. April 17-July 27, 1882 (Volume 112)
    - Daily cash blotter. August, 1882-October 19, 1883 (Volume 113)
    - Daily cash blotter. October 20, 1883-March 31, 1884 (Volume 114)
    - Daily cash blotter. November 11, 1884-November 25, 1885 (Volume 115)
    - Daily cash blotter. November 27, 1885-July 14, 1886 (Volume 115A)
    - Daily cash blotter. July 15, 1886-July 10, 1887 (Volume 116)
    - Daily cash blotter. May 27-July 18, 1889 (Volume 117)
    - Certificates of deposit stubs. June 1-July 24, 1880 (Volume 118)
    - Certificates of deposit stubs. July 26, 1880-May 30, 1881 (Volume 119)
    - Certificates of deposit stubs. May 31-November 14, 1881 (Volume 120)
    - Certificates of deposit stubs. May 1, 1882-October 15, 1883 (Volume 121)
    - Notes and bills payable and receivable; gives drawer, drawee, amount, date, and date paid. Customers include J.O. Dunbar, J.H. Behan, Isaac Clanton, Nellie Cashman, V.W. Earp, T.A. Sorin, John P. Clum, and others. June, 1880-April, 1882 (Volume 122)
    - Notes and bills receivable; see vol. 122. Customers include William Herring, J.H. Slaughter, G.E. Goodfellow, Godfrey Tribolet, and others. May, 1882-February, 1889 (Volume 123)
    - Collection register; gives drawer, drawee, due date, date paid, and amount. Customers include various companies, J.H. Behan, E.T. Hardy, Nellie Cashman, P.W. Smith, J.H. Slaughter, and others. August, 1881-March, 1884 (Volume 124)
    - Collection register. March, 1888-June, 1889 (Volume 125)
    - Accounts, L.M. Jacobs, Assignee. Itemized accounts of supplies purchased by various mining and milling companies; contains index. October, 1882-January, 1883 (Volume 126)
    - Financial records, Assignee. Includes rents collected, accounts and notes collected, disbursements, counsel fees and legal expenses, lists of creditors paid, and more. October, 1882-January, 1883 (Volume 127)
    - Financial records, Assignee. November, 1882-January, 1883 (Volume 128)
    - Statement with Correspondent Bank, Pima County Bank. June, 1880-November, 1881 (Volume 129)
    - Statement with Correspondent Bank, Pima County Bank. December, 1881-April, 1882 (Volume 130)
    - Statement with Correspondent Banks: Continental Bank, St. Louis; National Bank, Tucson; Pacific Bank; Union Trust Co., Chicago. 1883-1885 (Volume 131)
    - Statement with Correspondent Banks: First National Gold Bank, San Francisco; First National Bank, San Francisco; and Second National Bank, Santa Fe. 1883-1885 (Volume 132)
    - Statement with Correspondent Banks: Chemical National Bank, N.Y.; Farmers and Merchants' Bank, L.A.; First National Bank, El Paso; and Girard National Bank, Philadelphia. 1882-1889 (Volume 133)
    - Statement with Correspondent Banks: Bank of California, San Francisco; Bank of Tucson; Chemical National Bank, N.Y.; Continental Bank, St. Louis; First National Bank, Deming, N.M.; First National Bank, San Francisco; Second National Bank, Santa Fe; and Union Trust Co., Chicago. 1884-1886 (Volume 134)
    - Statement with Correspondent Banks: Bank of California, San Francisco; and Chemical National Bank, N.Y. 1886-1887 (Volume 135)
    - Statement with Correspondent Banks: Bank of California, San Francisco; and Continental Bank, St. Louis. 1886-1889 (Volume 136)
    - Statement with Correspondent Bank: Chemical National Bank, N.Y. February, 1884-March, 1885 (Volume 137)
    - Unidentified ledger; also includes minutes of one meeting of unidentified Jewish organization. Ledger, organized by customer, has name index; names include Bisbee Store, Alta Soap Co., Crystal Palace, Cora Davis, Geo. Cobb, E.T. Hardy, Dr. Goodfellow, several saloons and restaurants, and others. Meeting attended by several Cohen's, Summerfield's and Gotthelf's. May-July, 1882 (Volume 138)
    - Carbon records of stock transactions handled by Agency Pima County Bank, and carbon lists of creditors. 1882-1887 (Volume 139)
    - Statements (carbons) consist of record of amounts of checks paid by customers, chiefly mining companies. October 1, 1880-November 18, 1881 (Volume 140)
    - Telegrams (carbons); sent to correspondent banks regarding transactions. March 7, 1881-April 27, 1882 (Volume 141)
    - Letter book (carbons), contains partial index. Consists of one half page letters from P.W. Smith, Cashier to various correspondent banks and customers. June, 1880-November, 1881 (Volume 142)
    - Letter book (carbons). November, 1881-May, 1882 (Volume 143)
    - Letter book (carbons), letters to Pima County Bank. June 5, 1880-March 22, 1881 (Volume 144)
    - Letter book (carbons), letters to Pima County Bank. March 22, 1881-March 13, 1882 (Volume 145)
    - Letter book (carbons), letters to Pima County Bank. March 15-April 29, 1882 (Volume 146)
    - Letter book (carbons). April-July, 1885 (Volume 147)
    - Letter book (carbons). December, 1885-June, 1886 (Volume 148)
    - Letter book (carbons). December, 1886-December, 1887 (Volume 149)
    - Letter book (carbons). December, 1887-February, 1889 (Volume 150)
    - Letter book (carbons). March-July, 1889 (Volume 151)
    - Letter book (carbons). February, 1888-January, 1889 (Volume 152)
  - Bound volumes of Arizona National Bank, 1889-1909
    - Journal; daily transactions with customers including Tucsonans such as S.H. Drachman, Merrill P. Freeman, Samuel Hughes, J.K. Corbett, M. Samaniego, Colin Cameron, and Selim M. Franklin. July, 1889-June, 1890 (Volume 153)
    - Ledger; contains name index. Gives dates and amounts of transactions by customer. Customers include W.H. Barnes, Rosario Brena, J.B. Collins, A.V. Grossetta, Sabino Otero, Walter L. Vail, and others. July, 1889-June, 1890 (Volume 154)
    - Daily cash blotter. August 1, 1889-March 4, 1890 (Volume 155)
    - Daily cash blotter. August 12, 1891-March 25, 1892 (Volume 156)
    - Daily cash blotter. March 26-November 7, 1892 (Volume 157)
    - Daily cash blotter. November 10, 1892-May 4, 1893 (Volume 158)
    - Daily cash blotter. July 11, 1894-May 8, 1895 (Volume 159)
    - Daily cash blotter. May 9, 1895-January 7, 1896 (Volume 160)
    - Daily cash blotter. March 7-May 2, 1896 (Volume 161)
    - Daily cash blotter. July 1-October 22, 1896 (Volume 162)
    - Daily cash blotter. February 12-June 9, 1898 (Volume 163)
    - Daily cash blotter. June 10-October 5, 1898 (Volume 164)
    - Daily cash blotter. October 5, 1898-May 13, 1899 (Volume 165)
    - Daily cash blotter. May 15-December 18, 1899 (Volume 166)
    - Daily exchange records with correspondent banks. September 15, 1891-May 20, 1892 (Volume 167)
    - Daily exchange records with correspondent banks. December 16, 1892-September 11, 1893 (Volume 168)
    - Daily exchange records with correspondent banks. June 2, 1897-February 15, 1898 (Volume 169)
    - Daily exchange records with correspondent banks. February 16-November 21, 1898 (Volume 170)
    - Draft register. 1893-1895 (Volume 171)
    - Remittance register. September 23, 1890-January 18, 1892 (Volume 172)
    - Remittance register. November 11, 1896-September 10, 1897 (Volume 173)
    - Money orders (stubs); drawings on Hong Kong banks which give amounts, and names of payee and purchaser. Many are payable to Kwong Chong Wing Co.; purchasers include Wee Kee, Lee Aht, Hop Lee, Kam Wo and others. February 18, 1907-January 12, 1909 (Volume 174)
    - Seven deposit books for the Santa Cruz Valley Bank; customers were Wm. Reid, Pat F. Quinn, S.A. Waldon, Alexander Rossi, J.M. Dews, J. Warren, and S.A. Allis. 1889-1890 (Volume 175)
    - Letter book (carbons); consists of letters from Merrill P. Freeman, Cashier, to various banks and customers. January-March, 1890 (Volume 176)
  - Miscellaneous bound volume, circa. 1896
    - Gas Meter Accounts for Tucson customers; accounts are by person, residence or business and give dates and amounts of charges. circa. 1896 (Volume 177)